We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
It's almost like a maze in here.
Try not to get lost.
Okay.
Oww...
Are you okay?
Sorry.
What's this?
D-Dynamite!
Seriously?!
They're all damp now.
Don't worry; they won't explode.
Come on; get a move on.
We don't know when the enemy will come after us.
Right.
Looks like the blizzard died down.
Get ready.
Aye, sir.
We're going to take down Kimblee and his
two men from Central when we see an opening.
Aye, sir.
The Abyss
We're going to proceed with the mission with only the men currently present.
Don't tell anyone; not even soldiers from Northern Headquarters.
Hey-
Major Miles!
By "bring down", do you mean you're going to kill them?!
Of course.
I don't approve killing.
It's better to seal their abilities and beat information out of them.
Do you really think he'll tell the truth?
It's dangerous to keep him alive.
Then what about his men?
They may also be obeying him without choice after being turned into chimeras!
You have a point, but the keyword here is "may".
So you're going to kill them simply based on suspicion?
Same with Lieutenant General Raven! There were plenty of other methods-
Do not forget the law of Briggs.
If you let your guard down, you die.
Your softness may come back to kill you or one of your friends someday.
We don't need careless men in this land.
We're going to get rid of Kimblee and his two men.
I guess he's still a kid, after all.
Yeah.
Trying to settle matters without deaths in this world is a soft idea in itself.
But there was a time I was like that, as well.
I was, too.
You start to understand once you reach this age after living through many battles...
...that it's more difficult to keep someone alive rather than killing them.
The Elric Brothers chose the tougher path.
Strange guys, aren't they?
Yeah.
But I'm also a bit envious.
What's this "Rasayana" he writes about?
It's used to describe a miraculous medicine that extends one's lifespan.
I wonder if he's talking about a philosopher's stone?
Let's see...
What is this "Aurelian" that "turns all metal to gold,
and transforms old men to adolescents"?
It's a word for gold.
Most of this talks about immortality and gold.
Could it be because Mr. Scar's brother was heavily influenced by Eastern Alchemy from Xing?
Meaning?
In my country, we refer to the immortal as a "True Being".
It literally means "Perfect Being",
but because gold is a perfect metal,
there are times we refer to
a "True Being" as a "Golden Being".
I see. So a perfect being is a golden being.
Some say we refer to them that way because
the person who introduced alchemy to Xing...
...was an immortal man with golden hair and eyes.
Wow...
Golden hair and eyes? Sounds like Ed and Al!
Hey guys, come here!
I found the exit!
The sun's so bright!
Looks like we were able to get through the mountain.
The weather looks nice.
Let's head to Briggs now while we can.
Okay, everyone. Follow me-
Looks like the snow is pretty deep.
Help me!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
You can ride on my back, little girl.
Help me!
We'll make a path through the snow, so you can follow us.
You guys listening?!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Help me!
We appreciate it.
Hey!
Hey! Help me!!!
Is someone there?!
Al?!
Sir Alphonse?!
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
Are you okay, Al?!
You saved me...
I got stuck in a deep spot and ended up getting buried by the snow.
But why are you here, Al?
I crossed the mountain to get here before you guys.
You crossed the mountain... in that blizzard?
I get it. Instead of making a detour here, you took a straight path.
But why make such a reckless trip?
I have urgent news.
"Urgent news"?
The Central Army has infiltrated Briggs.
Apparently, Major General Armstrong has been summoned to Central, as well.
So it's dangerous to go there now.
What should we do?
We can't go back, either.
You're going to have to find somewhere else to hide out.
Yeah, like where?
Follow me.
Where are we going?
There should be a village by the name of Asbec not too far from here.
I've heard rumors my fellow countrymen have taken refuge in the slums there.
An Ishbalan slum, huh?
Doesn't seem like we have much of a choice.
Master, you rock! Let's get going!
But is it going to be okay?
What is?
Won't Sir Kimblee get suspicious if you disappear all of a sudden?
Nothing to worry about. Brother will keep everything under control.
Three from the third squadron.
Five from the fourth squadron.
Looks like we're all here.
Now, I want you all to begin searching in the districts you've been assigned.
Yes, sir.
Roger.
Let's move.
Aye, sir.
Come on, Alphonse.
Isn't this where you say "Okay"?
But it's really hard to move in this, Edward.
That's where I need you to do your best.
Come on, Kimblee's watching.
Wait up, Brother!
Walk faster.
Hey. Where are Kimblee and company searching?
There's a huge mine shaft at the center of the town, right?
Apparently, they're going to enter that and search the mine.
He said he's only going to take the men he brought from Central because he doesn't trust the soldiers up here.
He must have noticed already.
We're going to stall them.
Secure a position for sniping near the shaft mine.
Roger.
Search the entrance to the mine.
If you find multiple footprints, there's no doubt.
Yes, sir.
Can you do it?
At this distance, yes.
What's wrong?
Edward is...
What?
Kimblee, shouldn't you leave it to the soldiers from Briggs to search the mines?
I heard it's a labyrinth down there.
Seeing as how you went through the effort to persuade me out of it, this must be the place.
What are you talking about?
I just want to capture Scar-
Or are you trying to buy time to position the sniper?
So you noticed?
There's so much thirst for blood in the atmosphere; it would be odd not  to notice.
I didn't survive Ishbal for nothing.
It looks like they're talking about something. What should I do, sir?
Can you try to adjust your aim on Kimblee?
Yes.
Do it. Be very careful.
Aye, sir.
That bastard hid himself in snow!
Dammit!
Kimblee!
Damn you...
So you two are chimeras, too, huh?
Shit... I can't see a thing.
Well, they can't see me either...
...so I guess we're even-
Quit resisting, Fullmetal Alchemist!
There's no way for you to run since we can track you by scent!
Shut up!
Fullmetal!
What's going on?!
Where are you?! Respond!
Is that you, Major Miles?!
There are chimeras here!
And they've been trained to fight in places with low visibility!
Stay out of the smoke!
Oww...
Dammit... that just made me shorter...
Dynamite?
We're in a mine, all right!
Don't get too close now!
You do know what these are, right?
Are you stupid?
Those are probably too damp to use.
Do you two know what dynamite is made of?
Nitroglycerine?
Nitroglycol, chips of wood, and...
...ammonium nitrate, maybe?
Then what's ammonium nitrate made of?
Easy! Nitric acid and ammonia-
Ammonia?!
The smell!!!
What's that smell?!
Ammonia.
I guess there's a downside to having too keen a sense of smell.
These guys are toast.
So this is how you're going to act as soon as your hostages are released?
Don't know what you're talking about.
I'm just here to beat all the information you know out of you.
Christ, you're so hot-blooded.
Fighting with a young man like yourself during
my convalescence would surely break my bones.
And I don't have time to play with you either.
I guess I'll be using this, then.
He just saved me the trouble of searching for it!
He's fast!
Too slow!
He lost his philosopher's stone,
and his transmutation circle is no longer useable!
I-
"I win!"
Is that what you're thinking?
The determination not to kill.
An admirable policy.
But that's just asking for your enemy to take advantage of you during battle.
You should have killed me at that moment.
That softness is the cause of your defeat.
Did I fall down the mine shaft?
He's so heartless... he even got us into it...
Oww...
Dammit...
Where did Kimblee go...
You've got to be kidding me...
Hey!
Al! What's wrong?!
Sir Alphonse?!
Al?!
This isn't good.
I'm being drawn again...
What do you mean, "being drawn"?
Hey, what's wrong?
Al?
My soul...
...is being drawn toward...
Al!
Al?!
His soul is being drawn?
Sir Alphonse?!
Has this happened before?
Sir Alphonse! Pull yourself together!
I don't know!
PLACEHOLDER
Sir Alphonse!
Al?
Wake up, Al!
No...
Al!
Al!!!
What...
What should I do?!
Ed!
I can't... let her cry over something stupid like this...
Damn that Kimblee...
Yo, Fullmetal.
You alive?
Why did you save us?
You're hurt far worse than us.
Don't... get the wrong idea...
I... need someone to pull...
...this thing out... of my abdomen.
You're asking us to pull that steel frame out of you?
We're technically enemies, you know.
Yeah... please.
Well, we weren't ordered to kill you or anything.
Let's see.
But if we pull that out,
you're going to bleed out in an instant.
As soon as it leaves my body... I'm going to seal the wound... before I bleed to death.
Are you experienced in medical alchemy at all?
I've attempted human transmutation in the past... so I studied the main points.
"The main points"? I'm pretty sure your organs are shredded to pieces...
If you don't have a philosopher's stone like Sir Kimblee does...
That's why I'm going to use my life instead of a philosopher's stone...
What?!
It may shorten my life span by a bit, though...
Is that okay?
I don't have the time to dawdle.
If this injury was caused by my softness... then I have to clean up after myself.
I don't really get it, but you don't have much time to waste.
I'm pulling it out.
Do it, please.
I need to think of my life as a form of energy...
The same as... a philosopher's stone!
That's right!
Right now, I'm nothing more than
a philosopher's stone made out of one soul!
Think back, and try to remember that feeling!
That feeling...
...of using...
...life!!!
Is he dead?
Don't just write me off like that...
Oh, it worked?!
It's not completely healed.
It's just a temporary measure of linking the undamaged tissues... to stop the bleeding.
Then we need to get you to a doctor!
No, I don't have time... for that...
H-Hey!
I need to go after Kimblee...
...else... everyone will be in danger...
Geez...
Idiot.
There's no way he can win against him in this state.
What is it?
Whoa...
A philosopher's stone, huh?
The one Sir Kimblee had with him, right?
You don't need to refer to that freak as "Sir".
He dragged us into this.
You're right.
I guess that's the last time we see that bastard.
Yeah.
People will think we died here, so we're free.
And what should we do about him?
We can't just let him die.
He saved our lives.
Well said.
We need to find a doctor right away
once we get out of here.
Yeah.
The promise we never made
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
Koko ni arukara
After breaking the stalemate,
unforeseen ideas and actions open new paths.
The one to find the hidden truth obtains the key to victory.
But that's all a part of the accumulating daily life.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Signs of a
Counteroffensive
Episode 42, Signs of a Counteroffensive.
The beginning of war.